Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (VADP); Records apap304
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1937-2023; 7; 6.49 cubic ft.; 28.0 GB
  - Death Penalty Event "The Gospel of Life: Catholic Teaching & the Death Penalty at St. Mark's Catholic Church, Presentation with Second Revisions, 2012 December 13
  - Death Penalty Event at St. Thomas Aquinas Charlottesville, Flyer Draft, 2012 January 22
  - Death Penalty Event at St. Thomas Aquinas Charlottesville, Flyer Revised, 2012 January 22
  - Death Penalty Event at St. Thomas Aquinas Charlottesville, Notes, 2012 January 22
  - Death Penalty in the Media, 2015-2020 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Death Penalty in the South, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Death Penalty in the USA, 1990-2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Catholic Social Teaching" Presentation Slides, Cathedral of the Sacred Heart Richmond, 2014 March 9
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Catholic Social Teaching" Presentation Slides, St. Andrew's Catholic Church Roanoke, 2016 October 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Catholic Social Teaching" Presentation Slides, St. Andrew's Catholic Church Roanoke, Final, 2016 October 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Catholic Social Teaching" Presentation Slides, St. Andrew's Catholic Church Roanoke, Notes, 2016 October 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Catholic Social Teaching" Presentation Slides, St. Andrew's Catholic Church Roanoke, Revised, 2016 October 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Catholic Social Teaching" Presentation Slides, St. Andrew's Episcopal Church Norfolk, 2015 November 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia and Racial Justice" VADP Presentation Slides by Michael Stone, 2021 January 8
  - The Death Penalty in Virginia Pastors Meeting at Rising Mount Zion Baptist Church, Hand-Out, 2012 February 20
  - The Death Penalty in Virginia Pastors Meeting at Rising Mount Zion Baptist Church, Presentation, 2012 February 20
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, 5400 Club-Weinstein JCC Richmond, 2020 July 6
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, 5400 Club-Weinstein JCC Richmond, Model, 2020 July 20
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, 5400 Club-Weinstein JCC Richmond, Revised, 2020 July 6
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Christ Community Church, Charlosttesville, Shane Clairborne Event, 2018 September 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Christ Community Church, Charlottesville, 2019 February 16
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Church of the Epiphany, Richmond Virginia, 2020 February 11
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, Draft 1, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, Draft 2, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, Draft 3, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, Video, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, Video Final, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, ElderStudy Fredericksburg, Video Final Revised, 2017 October 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Episcopal Church Clergy Norfolk, 2016 May 17
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Loudon County Democrats Sterling, 2017 November 14
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Loudon County Democrats Sterling, Notes, 2017 November 14; 2017 November 13
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Loudon County Democrats Sterling, Standard Talk, 2018 March 1
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Richmond Rabbinical Council, Richmond, 2018 October 11
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Richmond Rabbinical Council, Richmond, 2018 November 15
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, St. George's Episcopal Church Fredericksburg, 2017 January 21
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, St. James Episcopal Church, Richmond, 2017 March 26
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Theophilus Club Norfolk, 2016 June 6
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, University of Virginia Law School Charlottesville, 2016 January 29
  - "The Death Penalty in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Westminster at Lake Ridge Prince William County, 2019 September 12
  - Death Penalty Inforamtion Center Death Row Exoneration Causes Chart, 2007-2017
  - Death Penalty Inforamtion Center Death Row Exoneration Causes Chart, Sharp Version, 2007-2017
  - Death Penalty Information Center "The Faces of Innocence" Graphic, 2013 February 11
  - Death Penalty Information Center Article "With Looming Exeuction and Serious Innocence Concerns, Calls Mount for Virginia to Grant Clemency to Ivan Teleguz", 2017 April 17
  - Death Penalty Information Center Study on Execution Secrecy, 2018 November
  - Death Penalty Information Center Study on Execution Secrecy, Cover Photo, 2018 November
  - Death Penalty Information Center Study on Execution Secrecy, Small Cover Photo, 2018 November
  - Death Penalty Information Center, Cost of California's Death Penalty Graphic, 2013 February 11
  - Death Penalty Lawyers, 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Death Penalty Location Link in VA, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Death Penalty Newspaper Articles (1 of 2), 1986-1990; 1992-1995; 1997-2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Death Penalty Newspaper Articles (2 of 2), 1986-1990; 1992-1995; 1997-2005; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Death Penalty Panel Flyer, Saint Thimas Aquinas Charlottesville, Revised, 2012 January 22
  - Death Penalty Presentations, 2011-2020 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Death Penalty Repeal Bill Signing VADP Remarks, 2021 March 24
  - Death Penalty Repeal Bill Signing with Govenor Ralph S. Northam, 2021 March 24
  - Death Penalty Stickers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Death Penalty Strategy Meeting Notes, 2016 January 6
  - "Death Row, Calls for Indifference, and Redemption of the Soul" by Corinna Barrett Lain, 2016 June
  - Death Row Exonerees, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Death Row Pen Pals, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Death Row Prisoners as Productive Members of Society, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Death Row Prisoners by State, 2019 July 15
  - Delaware Death Penalty, 2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Delma Banks, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dewey Cornell, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Discriminatory Practices in the Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Disrupting Death: How Dedicated Capital Defenders Broke Virginia's Machinery of Death" by Corinna Barrett Lain & Doug Ramseur, 2021 July 21
  - DNA Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - DNA Evidence, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - DNA on Trial, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - DNA Testing, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Doctors and Execution, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Doctors and Lethal Injections, 1980; 1982; 1985-1986; 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - DP and Deterrence, 1981-1982; 1985; 1988-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - DP and Execution Volunteers, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - DP and Mental Health, 1990; 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - DP and Mental Illness, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - DP and Mental Retardation, 1997; 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - DP and Politics, 2000; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - DP Articles, 2005-2007; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - DP Forum Fahey Ethal, Undated (Video-tape 16)
  - DP Hellen Pajama Lady, 1994 (Video-tape 17)
  - "The DP is Permissible", 1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - DPIC and Innocence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - DPIC Handouts, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - DPIC Weekly Updates, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - DPIC Weekly Updates, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Drawings by Death Row Inmate, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Encyclopedia Virginia "Anti-Lynching Law of 1928" Entry, 2008 November 6; 2012 June 12; 2016 January 22
  - Encyclopedia Virginia "Anti-Lynching Law of 1928" Webpage Screenshot, 2016 January 22
  - "Ending Capital Punishment in America: The Promise of and Challenges For Ending the Death Penalty" Presentation Slides by Cassandra Stubbs, ACLU Capital Punishment Project, 2020 October 24
  - Equal Justice and Fair Play, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Equal Justice Initiative "Lynching in America: Confronting the Legacy of Racial Terror County Data Supplement", 2020 February 7
  - Equal Justice Initiative Report "Reconstruction in America, Racial Violence after the Civil War, 1865-1876", 2020 June 17
  - Eric Nance, 2005; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Erich Reimer Bio, 2017 April 17
  - Ethics Articles, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ethics Class Death Penalty Presentation at St. Catherin's School in Richmond, 2012 July 9
  - Excerpt of Virginia House of Delegates virtual floor debate on Senate Bill 1165, a bill to abolish the death penalty" Video Recording, 2021 February 22
  - "The Execution of Child Offenders", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The Execution of the Innocent, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Execution Tables and Graphics, 1976-2018 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Execution Witness Bill, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "The Executioners", 2000 (Video-tape 18)
  - "The Executioners" A Play in One Act by Ellen H. Showell, 2000; 2019 November 27
  - Executions by Race Since 1986 Slide, 2018 November 1; 2020 November 20
  - "Executions Kill the Dream" VADP Lawn Sign, Undated (Oversized 3)
  - The Exonerated, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Extra Slides for Virginia Interfaith Center for Public Policy Workshop, 2021 January 19
  - Eye Witnesses, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Eye Witnesses and Exonerations, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Facing the Death Penalty, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Facts for Action, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - False Confessions, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fear of Crime and the Death Penalty Study, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Felon's Rights, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Fill the Field, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Final Wishes, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Florida Death Row, 2002-2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Flyers, 2003-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - FOIA Request to the Department of Corrections, 2015 May 1
  - FOIA Request to the Department of Corrections, 2015 July 9
  - Fredericksburg Free Lance Editorials "Drug costs enter death penalty debate", 2016 October 13
  - Fredericksburg Free Lance Star Editorial "Data on executions shouldn't be hidden", 2015 June 18
  - Fredericksburg Free Lance Star Editorial "No need for secrecy with execution drugs", 2015 July 3
  - Fredericksburg Free Lance Star Editorial "On-again, off-again sentence of death", 2016 December 28
  - Fredericksburg Free-Lance Star Letter to the Editor Submission Reciept, 2019 December 30
  - Free Lance-Star Moratorium Editorial "Gov.McAuliffe should impose a moratorium on the death penalty", 2015 March 24
  - Friends Committee on Common Wealth Legislature, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "From Hatred to Mercy", 2006 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "From Victim to Victimization", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Future Dangerousness, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - General Assembly, 2001; 2003-2004; 2006 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - The Genius of Death Row, Undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Georgetown Law, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Georgetown Law Journal Article "The Decline of the Virginia (and American) Death Penalty" by Brandon L. Garrett, 2017
  - Georgia Moratorium, 2006; 2003 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Gerald Zerkins Video Interview, 2021 July 15
  - Godanriver Article "Should the death penalty be put to death? The verdict is not unanimous", 2021 February 15; 2021 February 16
  - Gonzales, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Gospel of Life, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Governor Kaine, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Graphic of DNA Structure, 2017 October 16
  - The Guardian, Virginia Article "Virginia may be first in south to abolish death penalty and abandon 'legalized lynching', 2021 February 2
  - Guiding Message Guide from 8th Amendment Project, Draft, 2019 July 11
  - Gun Violence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Habeas Corpus, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Handouts, 2004-2007; Undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Harper's Magazine Article "A Matter of Life, The death penalty as a conservative conundrum", 2017 March
  - Harrisonburg Daily News Record Article "Stop Excecuting The Mentally Ill", 2017 December 11
  - Henry Heller Video Interview, Part 1, 2021 August 5
  - Henry Heller Video Interview, Part 2, 2021 August 5
  - Henry Heller Video Interview, Part 3, 2021 August 5
  - Herbert Bassette, Undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "The History of Electrocution in Virginia Is Racist and Should Not Be Continued", 2016 March 29
  - History of VADP, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Huffington Post Article "Govenor McAuliffe's Plan to Hide Source of Lethal Injection Drugs a Bad Idea", 2016 April 18
  - Illinois Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Image of Cain Slaying Abel, 2017 October 31
  - Image of the Catechism of the Catholic Church, 2013 February 11
  - Image of The Catholic Encyclopedia of 1911, 2017 October 31
  - Image of the Compendum of the Social Doctrine of the Church, 2017 October 31
  - Image of the Council of Trent, 2017 October 31
  - Image of David and Uriah, 2013 February 11
  - Image of David Brook, 2017 October 10
  - Image of Death Penalty Headlines, 2021 January
  - Image of GA Death Row Guard, Bobby Allen, 2013 February 19
  - Image of Jerry Givens, 2013 February 11
  - Image of Last Public Hanging, 1936; 2013 February 4
  - Image of Lee Boyd Malvo 1, 2017 October 12
  - Image of Lee Boyd Malvo 2, 2017 October 12
  - Image of Lynching 1, 1801 October 17; 2017 October 10
  - Image of Lynching 2, 2017 October 10
  - Image of "Moses slays Egyptian", 2013 February 11
  - Image of Nancy Goen, Daughter of Murdered State Trooper, 2013 February 11
  - Image of Pope Francis, 2017 October 31
  - Image of Pope John Paul the Second, 2013 February 11
  - Image of Pope John Paul the Second, 2013 February 11
  - Image of Pope John Paul the Second, 2013 February 11
  - Image of Pope Pius the Twelfth, 2017 October 31
  - Image of "The Prodigal Son", 2017 October 31
  - Image of Printed Op-Ed by Kristina Leslie "Death penalty repeal is essential to racial healing", 2020 July 3
  - Image of Printed Op-Ed by Kristina Leslie "Death penalty repeal is essential to racial healing" cropped version, 2020 July 3
  - Image of Robert Gleason, 2013 February 11
  - Image of "Sabbath", 2017 October 31
  - Image of "Saint Paul Conversion on the Road to Damascus", 2013 February 11
  - Image of Saint Thomas Aquinas, 2017 October 31
  - Image of Saint Thomas Aquinas Icon, 2017 October 31
  - Image of "Salvation", 2017 October 31
  - Image of Syringe, 2013 February 11
  - Image of "Throwing Stone", 2013 February 11
  - Image of Virginia Electric Chair, 2013 February 4
  - Imagine Festival, Undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Imagine the End of the Death Penalty, Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - "Indecent and Illegal the Death Penalty Against Child, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Indiana Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Indigent Counsel, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Indigent Defense in the USA, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Indigent Defense in Virginia, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Ineffective Assistance of Counsel, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Ineffective Counsel, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - In Lieu of Flowers, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Innocence, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Innocence and the DP, 1999-2000; 2004 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Innocence Project of the National Capital Region, Undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Innocence Protection Act, 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Inside Update Recording Video, 2020 April 17
  - Institute for Actual Innocence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - The Intercept Article "The Long Shadow of Virginia's Death Penalty", 2021 April 11
  - International Death Penalty, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - International Justice Project Equal Protection and Expanded Guide, Undated (Cd 2)
  - International Juvenile DP, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - International Prayer for Peace, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Iron and the Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - "Is He too Young to Die", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Italy Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Ivan Teleguz and Ricky Jovan Gray Case Summaries, 2015 November 16
  - Ivan Teleguz Case, Clemency Appeal, 2017 March 1
  - Ivan Teleguz Case Summary, 2017 May 13
  - Jack Hicks, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Jack Payden-Travers Video Interview, 2021 July 15
  - James Reid, 1996; 2001; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jerry Givens on BBC podcast, 2006 May 24
  - Joe Giarratano, 1991; 2000; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - John Warner, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, "Review if Virginia's System of Capital Punishment" Commission Draft, 2001 December 10
  - Jon Sheldon Video Interview Part 1, 2021 July 15
  - Jon Sheldon Video Interview Part 2, 2021 July 15
  - Jordan Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journey of Hope, 1995 (Video-tape 19)
  - Just Children, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Justice Project, Undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Justice Stevens, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Juvenile Corrections in Iraq, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty, 2000; 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty, 2003-2004; 2006; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Book Mark, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Cases, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Curriculum, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Materials, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Packet Draft, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Resources, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Resolution Draft, 2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Study Curriculum, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Juvenile DP Articles, 1985; 1987-1992; 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Juvenile DP Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Juvenile DP Initiative, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Juvenile Execution Materials, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Juvenile Murder Cases, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Kaine, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Kansas Cherley, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Keith Harward Digital Op-Ed Inside Page Image, 2019 December 22
  - Keith Harward Op-Ed Digital Front Page Image, 2019 December 22
  - Keith Harward Op-Ed Printed Front Page Image, 2019 December 22
  - Keith Harward Op-Ed Printed Front Page Image, Small, 2019 December 22
  - Keith Harward Printed Op-Ed Inside Page Image, 2019 December 22
  - Kent Willis Video Interview, 2021 August 5
  - Kentucky Death Penalty, Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Kerry Cook, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Kids Death Penalty Answers, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "Killers", 1937 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - King DP Sermon, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Kristina Leslie Video Interview, 2021 July 15
  - LA Progressive Article "Reflections on the End of the Death Penalty", 2021 March 16; 2021 March 27
  - LA Times Op-Ed "Can Virginia reject past and ban the death penalty?", 2021 January 28
  - Lack of Benefits of the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Lancaster Online Op-Ed "DA Stedman disregarded my opposition to the death penalty", 2015 March 22; 2021 November 13
  - Lapeine De Mort, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Larry King Sniper Trials, Undated (Video-tape 20)
  - "The Legacy of Wrongful Convictions ", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Legality of Execution, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Legislative Prep Materials, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Legislative Strategy Template, Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Lethal Injections, 1998; 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Lethal Injections Articles, 1982; 1985-1999; Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Lethal Injections Articles, 1998; 1990; 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Lethal Injections Debate, 1993-1994; 1998 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Lethal Injections Research, 1980-1982; 1988; 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Letter to Rina Shah Bharara with Copy of Brian Stolarz Book, 2017 June 6
  - Letter to Russ Moulton, Draft, 2015 May 20
  - Liberty Prison Outreach The Choice is Yours, Undated (Video-tape 20)
  - Life on Death Row, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - "Life Without Fear", 2002 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Linell Patterson Video Interview, 2021 August 5
  - List of Delegates & Candidates who publically supported clemency for William Morva, 2017 November 9
  - List of Inmates, Undated; 1987 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - List of People Sending Ricky Gray Clemency Messages to Governor, 2017 January 12
  - Loudoun Times Article "Pace of death sentences, executions slows in Virginia", 2015 May 5
  - Lynchburg News Advance Article "Anti-death penalty activist Helen Prejean speaks at Randolph College", 2018 March 28
  - Lynchburg News Advance Editorial "Cloaking the Death Penalty in Secrecy is Bad Policy" Paul Ebert, 2016 April 24
  - Lynchburg News Advance Op-Ed "Cabezas and Thissen: Death Penalty for Mentally Ill Defendants?", 2017 December 17
  - Lynching Article in Newspaper, 1927 December 1; 2017 October 10
  - Lynching Postcard Book Listing, 2000 February 1; 2017 October 17
  - Map of U.S. Lynchings and Executions Slide, 2020 November 20
  - Marilyn Stark Video Interview, 2021 June 15
  - Marketing Plan for "Closing the Slaughterhouse: The Inside Story of Death Penalty Abolition in Virginia", 2022 February 27
  - Martinsville Seven, 2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Maryland Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Massachusetts Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Matthew Engle Video Interview, 2021 August 5
  - Matthew Mangino Op-Ed "Virginia begins down the road of radical reconciliation", 2021 February 17
  - Mental Illness and the Death Penalty, Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Mental Retardation and the Death Penalty, 1999; 2002; Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Mercy for William Morva: Trailer Still, 2017 May 12
  - Mexicans on Death Row, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Mexico Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Mexico v. USA, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Michael Graham, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Michael Morales, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Michigan Death Penalty, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Miller-EL, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Miscarriage of Justice, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Missouri Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "The Modern Death Penalty Era in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Osher Lifelong Learning Institute, University of Virginia Charlottesville, Draft, 2018 November 12
  - "The Modern Death Penalty Era in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Osher Lifelong Learning Institute, University of Virginia Charlottesville, Final, 2018 November 12
  - "The Modern Death Penalty Era in Virginia" Presentation Slides, Osher Lifelong Learning Institute, University of Virginia Charlottesville, Version 1, 2018 November 12
  - Moral Arguments Against the Death Penalty, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Morality and the DP, Undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Moratorium and Religion, 1987; 1991; 1998-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Moratorium in other States, Undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Moratorium Now! Materials, 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Moratorium Study, Undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Morocco Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Moussaoui Trial, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Muhammad and Malvo, Undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Murder Victim Family Members Press Conference Screen Shot, 2019 November 22